# Nariman Abdullin Lead Software Developer



## **Profile**

Senior Java backend developer with 10+ years of experience and middle Korlin backend developer with 2 years of experience. Experienced in Java, Kotlin, Spring Boot, WebFlux, Backend development, BigData stack (Spark/Hadoop). Former experience in Invest Banking (middle/back office).

# Experience

### **Huawei Russian Research Institutes**

May 2022 – present (2 years)

#### **Lead Software Developer**

Joined existing project on Kotlin and drove the refactoring to simplify engine for static analysis and architecture of micro-services.

Introduced S3 storage for micro-services. Implemented a new service for providing and library for processing vulnerabilities (OSV format). Implemented CI on GitHub Actions.

Technology Stack: Kotlin MPP, Spring Boot, Java, Kubernetes, Gradle, Git.

### Russian Technology Center of BNP Paribas Bank

February 2020 - May 2022 (2 years)

#### **Lead Software Developer**

Joined existing project and drove the migration to the newest technologies.

Developed an internal framework for providing access to static data: Spring boot based Web Service application with generated model (Avro based). Implemented CI on Jenkins.

Technology Stack: Java, Spring boot, Avro, Maven, Git.

## **Russian Technology Center of Deutsche Bank**

*June* 2013 – *February* 2020 (7 years)

#### **Senior Software Developer**

Server side application based on the internal framework on Spring Framework and <u>disruptor/ring buffer</u>. *Technology Stack:* Java, Spring Boot, Protobuf, Maven/Ant, Git/SVN

Data lake for storing trading data from different sources built with Hadoop/Spark. Impala for ad hoc queries. Supported migration from Spark 1.6 to Spark 2.x. Maintained an internal framework for processing upon on Spark (long running spark submit app with incoming events to process new batches).

Technology Stack: Scala, Java, Spark, Hadoop, Akka, Maven, Git.

Technical lead in both projects teams. Supported DevOps and CI/CD processes in projects: implemented CI on TeamCity and CD on UrbanCode Deploy.

## **Education**

September 2007 - June 2014

<u>Bauman Moscow State Technical University</u>, Specialist Degree. Faculty of Informatics and Control System of Specialization: department of Software for Computers and Automation Systems.

#### **Certificates:**

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer

Architecting with Google Kubernetes Engine: Foundations
Google Cloud Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure